It is true what they say:
俗話說得沒錯
Pregnant bellies look like a drum.
肚子大當鼓打
I'm so pregnant that my guitar doesn't fit anymore.
我已經腫到不能拿吉他
So I'm going to play my songs on this drum.
所以生產前我打算用鼓伴奏
It sounds really cool!
聽起來超酷的
Listen,listen.
你們聽
Smelly cat,smelly cat
臭臭貓，臭臭貓
What are they feeding you?
他們餵你吃什麼？
That sounds great!
菲比，太吊了
I know! And I've only been playing for an hour.
我知道！而且我才練了1小時
菲比…
-What are you doing here? -I came to ask you a big favor.
你怎麼來了？ 我來請你幫個大忙
Don't tell me you want to keep more stuff in my uterus.
別說你還想塞東西進來
Okay. Now,see.
不…是這樣的
I want to name the girl baby Leslie.
我想幫女孩取名萊絲莉
And Frank wants to name one of the boy babies...
法蘭克想叫其中一個男孩
...Frank Jr.,Jr.
法蘭克二世二世
Wouldn't that be Frank lll?
那不就是法蘭克三世？
Don't get me started.
說了我就有氣
Anyway,since there are three babies...
既然有三個寶寶
...and we both got to put our names in...
我們又一人取了一個名字
...we would be truly honored if you would name the other boy baby.
我們想請你替另一個男孩命名
That's so nice!
好棒喔
Cougar.
美洲獅
Think about it.
你想一下
The One with Rachel's New Dress
本集播出：「姓名學」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
I left a bra drying in there.
我有一件胸罩還在晾
Will your son think it's yours and be traumatized?
班會不會以為是你的 而心靈受創？
Mommy can have a wife. Daddy can have a bra.
媽咪可以有老婆 爹地就可以有胸罩
It's time to go.
該走了
See,that clock's a little fast.
不，那個鐘快了一點
We still have 17 minutes.
我們還有17分鐘
What can we do in 17 minutes...
什麼事可以在17分鐘內
...twice?
做兩次？
Well,that's ambitious.
野心真大
You can ignore that.
別理它
That's your son.
是卡蘿帶你兒子來了
Believe me,when he's older, he'll understand.
等他長大一定會諒解
I'll be right there.
羅斯 馬上來
This is Carol and Susan.
艾蜜莉，這是卡蘿和蘇珊
-It's so nice to finally meet you. -You too.
總算見到你了 我也是
-Susan will be in London next week. -I've never been there.
蘇珊下星期要去倫敦拍廣告 對，我好興奮，我沒去過
-I'll show you around. -Great!
我來當地陪 太好了
Also,I was hoping to catch a show. Any suggestions?
我還想看秀，你有什麼建議？
There's tons of terrific stuff.
有很多都很棒…
I'll go with you.
我陪你去
對不起
Look at you two bonding.
你們可真聊得來
Making us late for the airport.
去機場都快來不及了
Are you all right?
你沒事吧？
It's just us getting along is difficult for him...
他沒事 他不喜歡我們處得來
...because he doesn't like me.
因為他不喜歡我
Come on. That's....
拜託，我…
It's true.
沒錯
How did we lose?
沒人對打也會輸？
Do we have a baby name yet?
名字想好了嗎？
No. It's so hard!
還沒，好難喔
I went through this book and found nothing.
翻這本書也沒收穫
I want a name that's really strong and confident.
我想取個勇猛有自信…
You know? Like...Exxon!
例如愛克爽
It certainly worked for that Valdez kid.
很適合阿拉斯加小孩
You want a strong name? How about The Hulk?
你要勇猛的名字？ 綠巨人如何？
I'm not sure about Hulk, but I like a name starting with "The".
綠巨人不太好 不過我喜歡什麼「人」的
You want a good name, go with Joey.
想取好名字？就取喬伊
Joey's your pal,your buddy.
喬伊是好朋友，好兄弟
Where is everybody? They're hanging out with Joey!
人都在哪裡？都跟喬伊在一起
If you're going to name him Joey, you should name him Chandler.
要取喬伊，還不如取錢德
Chandler's funny,sophisticated, and very lovable...
錢德風趣、世故，一旦瞭解他
...once you get to know him.
就會覺得他很可愛
Joey's lovable too.
喬伊也很可愛
But with Joey,if you need him, he'll be there.
重要的是當你需要喬伊 他就會出現
Chandler will be there too. He might be a little late...
錢德也會出現，或許會慢一點
...but he'll be there. And he'll bring you cold soda...
不過他一定會出現 他還會帶冰汽水來
...if what you need him for is that you're really hot.
如果你找他是因為你很熱的話
What do you say?
你覺得呢？
I like the idea of naming him after someone I love.
跟心愛的人同名的想法很好
Joey and Chandler are both great names.
喬伊和錢德都是很棒的名字
All right,I don't
但是我不… 了
Maybe I'll just name him The Hulk.
或是就叫綠巨人好
I shouldn't have mentioned it. I wanted to name my kid that.
我不該提的 我想留給我小孩用
If you hoped to sleep with Joshua, which one would you wear?
要是你想跟約書亞上床 會穿哪一件？
It creeps me out choosing other people's sex clothes.
我覺得幫別人挑性感睡衣很怪
I'm sorry. I'm just so excited.
對不起，我太興奮了
I've been waiting for months. I got my hair colored.
我等了好幾個月 我跑去染髮，
I got new sheets. I'm making him a very fancy meal.
換了床單 還幫他煮大餐
What am I making him,by the way?
我在煮什麼？
A frisee salad with goat cheese and pine nuts...
什錦沙拉，有羊酪、松子
...wild rice,roasted asparagus and salmon en croute.
菰米飯、烤蘆筍和鮭魚麵包丁
I thought I was making him filet mignon.
我不是要做腓力牛排？
You decided to make salmon because you had some left over.
本來是，但餐廳的鮭魚有剩 所以你決定煮鮭魚
Then you realized if you bitched, then you would stop cooking...
然後你想到要是你抱怨 「你」就會罷煮
...and you would have to make your famous baked potato and Diet Coke.
你就得上烤馬鈴薯加健怡可樂
I really get crabby when I cook.
「我」煮菜時火氣真大
Why go through all this trouble? He's a guy.
你何必這麼麻煩，他是個男人
You'd serve the potato and he'd still want to have sex with you.
你上馬鈴薯 他還是會想跟你上床
That is not how I operate.
那不是我的作風
We've got to get a new game.
我們得換一種遊戲
So Emily called last night.
艾蜜莉昨晚打電話來
And now you're giving me the message?
你現在才轉告我？
Turns out that Emily is just crazy about Susan.
結果艾蜜莉愛死蘇珊了
They're going to the theater together.
她們一起去看戲
They're going to dinner.
她們一起吃晚飯
They're going horseback riding!
她們一起去騎馬
God,Susan is so fun!
蘇珊真會玩
Look,this is just a little too familiar.
這個情節太熟悉了一點
For six months before Carol and I split up...
我和卡蘿分手前整整半年
...all I heard was, "My friend Susan is so smart.
我整天只聽到 「我朋友蘇珊好聰明」
My friend Susan is so funny. My friend Susan is so great."
「我朋友蘇珊好風趣」 「我朋友蘇珊好棒」
You think something could happen between Emily and Susan?
你覺得艾蜜莉和蘇珊 會擦出火花？
Hey,they're going to the gym together!
她們一起上健身房耶
Two women...
兩個女人…
...stretching!
...劈腿拉筋
They take a steam,things get playful. Didn't you see Personal Best?
她們洗蒸汽浴，開始互相逗弄 你們沒看過「登峰造極」嗎？
No,but I'm gonna!
沒，但我一定要看
Hi! You're crazy.
先生，你瘋了
Emily is straight.
艾蜜莉是異性戀
How do you know? We thought Carol was straight.
你怎麼知道？ 我們原先也以為卡蘿是異性戀
Yeah,definitely. I don't like the name Ross.
我肯定不喜歡羅斯這個名字
What a weird way to kick me when I'm down!
你落井下石的方式還真怪
No,I meant for the baby.
我是說寶寶的名字
What's wrong with Ross?
羅斯有什麼不好？
Something like this would never happen to The Hulk,you know.
綠巨人就不會遇上這種事
That's not true.
誰說的
In The Incredible Hulk,number 72, Dr. Bruce Banner found....
「綠巨人」第72集裡 布魯斯班納博士發現…
You know....
Never mind. My girlfriend's a lesbian.
不重要，我女朋友是同性戀
I'm definitely going to go with either Joey or Chandler.
我決定不是喬伊就是錢德
You gotta pick Joey!
你一定要選喬伊
Name one famous person named Chandler.
有哪個名人叫錢德？
Raymond Chandler.
雷蒙錢德（勒） （著名冷硬派推理小說作家）
Someone you didn't make up.
你捏造的人不算
There are no famous Joeys. Except for...
喬伊才沒有名人，除了…
...Joey Buttafucco.
喬伊巴塔富寇
Yeah,that guy really hurt us.
他的確是我們的心頭之痛
How about a compromise then? What if it's...
加起來除以二如何？例如…
...Chan-no-ey?
錢道伊？
Joey? Think about it. He'll never be President.
喬伊？你想嘛 他絕對當不上總統
There will never be a President Joey.
絕對不會出現喬伊總統
I didn't want to bring this up.
聽著，我本來不想提的
Chandler is the stupidest name I've heard in my life!
但錢德是我聽過最蠢的名字
It's not a name! It's barely even a word.
它根本不是名字 連個詞都不是
It's like chandelier but it's not!
它有點接近錢包，但又不是
Then,you put it together with Bing and forget about it.
再配上「賓」就更別提了
It's a stupid,stupid,non-name!
它是個蠢到爆的非名字
You're right. I have a horrible,horrible name.
天哪 你說得對，我的名字爛透了
I'm sorry,man. I'm sorry.
對不起，我不是…對不起
So I guess it's Joey then.
所以就是喬伊羅
This is so nice. Thank you for doing this.
真好，謝謝你這麼費心
Please! Cooking soothes me.
別客氣，烹飪能舒緩我的心
So dig in!
吃吧 好
It all looks so good.
看起來都好好吃
Oh,my God.
天哪
I know. My God,this rice is so
我知道，天哪，這個飯好…
I am so good!
我的手藝真好
Behind you.
你後面
They used to live here, and sometimes they migrate back over.
沒事，它們以前住這裡 有時會遷徙回來
Is there some way that they could not be here?
能不能讓它們不要在這裡
Farm birds really kind of freak me out!
我最怕家禽了
好
Here we go.
出去
There you go!
Hey! How'd you do that?
你們怎麼會敲門？進來
All gone.
都走了
So,farm birds,huh?
家禽是吧？
It's my only weird thing,I swear.
我只有這個怪癖，我發誓
I would have told you. I didn't know that they'd be here.
我不知道會有雞鴨 否則我會告訴你
Can I serve you a little
要不要來點…
What?
怎麼了？
Nothing.
沒事
It's just that I know that they're still out there.
只是我知道它們還在
They're across the hall. That's two doors away.
它們在對門，隔著兩道牆
It'll take them a long time to peck their way back over here.
它們得啄很久才能把牆啄穿
That's not funny.
一點也不好笑
Would you feel better if we went someplace else?
那要不要換個地方？
We could pack this stuff up and go to your apartment.
我們可以把東西打包去你家
They're working on it. It's a mess.
我家正在裝修，一團混亂
I'm staying at my parents' house. We could go there.
不過我們可以去我父母家
They're out of town.
你父母家？ 對，他們出國了
It's a huge place, and it's got this gorgeous view.
那裡地方很大，視野很棒
It'd be very romantic.
會很浪漫
-What do you say? -Yeah,that works.
如何？ 好啊
They can smell the fear.
它們聞得出恐懼
How's Ben?
班好嗎？
I asked if he wanted to eat. He said no.
我問他要不要吃東西 他說不要
I asked if he wanted to sleep. He said no.
我問他要不要睡覺，他說不要
I asked what he wanted to do. He said no.
我問他想做什麼，他說不要
So he's sweeping.
所以他在掃地
Any word from Susan?
有蘇珊的消息嗎？
She said she's having so much fun with Emily.
她說她跟艾蜜莉玩得很開心
By the by,did it ever occur to you that...
對了，你有沒有想過
...maybe they might be having a little too much fun?
她們或許太開心了一點？
What's too much fun?
什麼叫太開心？
The kind of fun you and Susan had when we were married.
我們結婚時 你和蘇珊的那種開心
Oh,my God! You are so paranoid.
天哪，你真會亂想
Am l?
是嗎？
Susan is in a loving, committed relationship.
艾蜜莉我不知道 但蘇珊和我的關係很穩定
Carol,so were we.
卡蘿，我們也是
Just imagine for a moment...
你就想像一下
...that Susan meets someone, and they hit it off.
蘇珊認識了別人 她們一拍即合
They're coming back from the theater, and they stop at a pub for drinks.
她們從劇院回來 去酒吧喝個小酒
They're laughing.
有說有笑
Someone innocently touches someone else.
有人不經意的碰了另一個人
There's electricity.
有火花
It's new. It's exciting.
感覺很新鮮，很刺激
Are you saying there isn't the slightest possibility...
你敢說完全沒有可能...
...of something happening?
...出事？
-Maybe. -Oh,my God!
或許有 天哪！
I didn't really believe it until you just said it!
聽你一說我才真的信了
None of the other kids believed me, but I swear that duck pushed me.
別的小朋友都不信 但那只鴨子真的推我
This place is fabulous!
這裡真豪華
This is the downstairs living room.
我帶你參觀，這是樓下的客廳
There's two living rooms?
有兩個客廳？
Growing up here,this place must have been a real babe magnet.
你一定靠這裡把到很多美眉
It would have been, but my parents just moved here.
應該會，但我父母剛搬來
You should know this place is a real babe magnet.
你可以靠這裡把到很多美眉
Want to make out?
要親熱嗎？
Why don't I put the food in the fridge...
這樣吧，我去把吃的冰起來
...and we can eat it later?
我們待會再吃
That sounds like a plan.
聽起來不錯
Is there a place that I could go freshen up?
哪裡可以讓我梳洗一下？
Just down the hall and second door to your left.
有，直走左邊第二個門
-Hi,darling. -What are you doing here?
兒子 你們怎麼回來了？
-We cut the trip short. -France sucks!
我們提前結束行程 法國爛透了
This may be a little weird, but I've got a date here.
情況有點特殊，我帶了人回來
Say no more.
瞭解
We'll grab some food,go upstairs and be out of your hair.
我們拿了吃的就上樓不妨礙你
That'd be great. So you didn't get to ltaly?
那就好，所以你們沒去意大利
Yep. Sucks!
沒有，爛
Hi,you!
你來了
Oh,my God!
天哪
I know. I can do more than cook.
我知道，我不只會做菜
I like her. She seems smart.
我喜歡她，她似乎很聰明
Rachel,my parents.
瑞秋，我爸媽
So nice to meet you.
很高興認識你們
Joshua,that $500 was for groceries.
約書亞 那5百元是給你買日用品的
What,this? Oh,no. That's not what it is.
什麼？這…不，你們誤會了
Okay,I work in fashion.
我在時裝界工作
And this is a real dress,actually.
這是正式的洋裝
They're wearing it in Milan.
米蘭正在流行
Part of my job is to wear the clothes and see how people respond.
我也必須試穿衣服 觀察一般人的反應
Then I report back to my superiors at Bloomingdale's.
然後回報給布魯明戴爾的上司
Obviously,in this case...
這次...
...I am going to report back:
...我顯然得回報說
"U.S.A. not ready."
「美國，尚嫌大膽」
Maybe in L.A.
洛杉磯或許可以
There you go!
也對 有道理
Have you kids eaten yet?
你們吃過飯了嗎？
We were going to do that after. I mean,next.
我們想等事後…不是 正要吃
Why don't we all get something to eat?
我們餓死了 大家一起出去吃吧
No use wasting this baby just lying around the house.
也好 穿著它窩在家裡太可惜了
So we'll go eat.
所以我們去吃飯
You'll wear that.
你就穿那樣
We'll be eating and, of course,you'll be wearing that.
你就穿那樣吃飯
I am sorry about what I said.
我為我說的話道歉
Nope,you're right. It is a ridiculous name!
不，你說得對 這個名字太可笑了
It's not bad.
也沒那麼糟
Yes,it is!
當然有
From now on,I have no first name.
從此以後，我沒有名字
You're just Bing?
你就叫賓？
I have no name.
我無名無姓
So what are we supposed to call you?
那我們要叫你什麼？
Okay,for now,temporarily, you can call me...
好，你們就暫時叫我…
...Clint.
克林
No way are you cool enough to pull off "Clint."
你才不夠酷
What name am l cool enough to pull off?
那我可以叫什麼？
Gene.
金
It's Clint.
克林
It's Clint!
就是克林
Bye,Gene.
金，再見
It's Clint!
是克林，克林
What's up with Gene?
金有什麼不好？
You wore your nightie to dinner?
你穿你的睡衣去吃飯？ 沒錯
The best part was when the waiter spilled water down my back.
最精彩的是 我背後被服務生潑到水時
I jumped up and my boob popped out.
我一跳，咪咪彈了出來
It's all right. I got nice boobs.
沒關係，我的胸型很漂亮
I just picked up a message from Emily.
我剛收到艾蜜莉的留言
She and Susan are going to a poetry reading together.
她和蘇珊要一起去讀詩會
-So? -So?
所以呢？ 所以呢？
Poetry?
詩耶？
Susan's gay.
蘇珊是同志…
They're being gay together!
她們有志一同
Emily's straight.
艾蜜莉是異性戀
Oh,wake up!
你醒醒吧
Carol really messed you up.
卡蘿真的把你害慘了
Excuse me?
你說什麼？
She turned you into this untrusting,crazy,jealous...
她害你變成不信任別人 瘋瘋癲癲愛吃醋的...
...sycophant!
...讒臣
So I don't know what "sycophant" means, but the rest is right.
我不知道讒臣是什麼 但其他都沒說錯
What are you talking about? I am not a crazy,jealous person.
我哪有瘋瘋癲癲愛吃醋
She's right.
她說得沒錯
When we were together,you got upset about Mark,and there was nothing.
以前你老愛吃馬克的醋 其實根本沒事
This makes sense.
太有道理了 才怪
It does not!
當然有道理
In high school, you weren't jealous at all...
高中時你從來沒吃過醋...
...even though all your girlfriends cheated on you.
...即使你每個女友都不忠
So up until '92,'93, he was very trusting.
一直到92、93年 他都很信任別人
Then '94 hit,Carol left him, and bam! Paranoid City!
然後94年來臨，卡蘿離開他 砰！紐約鬼影幢幢
Absolutely!
就是這樣
This is so fun!
好好玩喔
This is not fun!
一點也不好玩
All we're trying to say is...
我們只想說...
...don't let what happened with Carol ruin what you've got with Emily.
...別讓你和卡蘿的事 破壞你和艾蜜莉的感情
The '92 Ross wouldn't.
92年的羅斯就不會
I still think I was right about that Mark thing.
我還是覺得馬克一定有問題
Well,you know what? I hope Emily is a lesbian.
什麼？你知道嗎？ 我希望艾蜜莉是同志
Drumroll.
擊鼓
All right.
好…
Help!
幫個忙
Am I a Mark or a John?
我是馬克還是約翰？
You're not tall enough to be a Mark.
你當馬克不夠高
But you might make a good Barney.
你或許可以當個好巴尼
Look,I am serious.
我是認真的
Tomorrow at 3:30,I'm going to the courthouse.
明天3點半我就要上法院
You're going through with this?
你真的要改名？
This name has held me back my entire life.
這個名字拖累了我一輩子
It's why kids picked on me and why I never do well with women.
害我被其他小朋友找碴 女人運很差
So tomorrow,I'll either be Mark Johnson or John Markson.
明天4點起我不是馬克約翰森 就是約翰馬克森
You've got problems because of you, not your name!
你的問題在於你，與名字無關
This has got to stop! Chandler is a great name.
別再鬧了，錢德這個名字很棒
In fact....
事實上…好
I'm sorry,I know you wanted me to name the baby Joey.
對不起 我知道你希望寶寶叫喬伊
I'm going to name the baby Chandler.
但我要…我要讓他叫錢德
Really?
真的？
But you have to keep the name too.
對，但你也得保留這個名字
Okay,thanks!
好，謝了
You want to hug it out?
要不要抱一下？ 好
I'm going to go tell Frank and Alice right now!
我現在就去告訴法蘭克他們
Bye,Pheebs!
菲比 再見
-Nice luggage. -I was going to say.
很棒的行李箱 我正要說
I missed you too.
我好想你 我也是
-Thanks,I had a great time. -So did l.
謝謝你，我玩得很開心 我也是
No tongue.
不是舌吻